<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essays on Pietro Grandinetti</title>
    <link>https://pete.world/tags/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essays on Pietro Grandinetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pete.world/tags/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Coaching Habit</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2021/01/review-coaching-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2021/01/review-coaching-habit/</guid>
      <description>At times, a book falls in your hands as if it was no coincidence.
This is pretty much what happened to me with The Coaching Habit (M.B. Stanier). Great book, for the records.
As it happened, I have been thinking a lot recently about management, business direction, and what motivates people at work. Then, on one of the last days of 2020, I received a note about this book in the newsletter sent by the instructors of the MOOC Learning to Learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hamster-Writer Loop</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/12/loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/12/loop/</guid>
      <description>Writing is like engineering my thoughts.
Every idea that comes from a sharp mind can be expanded into a full essay. If you simply start with a single, short sentence and then elaborate the thoughts within and beyond it, like engineering them, the essay will be there in front of your eyes.
At first, it will feel as if the sentence is crystal clear. Nothing to add. Well, give it another chance, and if you still have the same feeling then just stare at it a bit longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Easy Story</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/11/easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/11/easy/</guid>
      <description>Every day is yet another day I am impressed by the amount of talking, reading and writing made about waking up early.
Frankly, it seems to come mostly from average writers trying to make catchy titles: How I changed my life waking up at 5 am.
I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up at 6 am five days a week for many years. Sometimes six days out of seven. And not because of some principle or propaganda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Freelancer Journey</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/07/freelancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/07/freelancer/</guid>
      <description>I was 23 when I heard the word freelancer the first time. I became fascinated with it, and in the following three years I devoted a great deal of energy and passion towards becoming a freelancer.
I believe I was able to hit some pretty good milestones, but I also hit some very hard walls along the way. I want now to describe in detail the actions I took from the day I decided to become a freelancer, till the day I stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindshift</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/mindshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/mindshift/</guid>
      <description>Changes in life, sometimes, they just happen.
Why do they more often happen to some people? What traits have these people in common?
For the changes I am talking about, there is one big trait in common: these people are smart.
What is wrong with smart people, why aren&amp;rsquo;t they ever satisfied? Why do they need changes?
To be sure, being content is a great personal quality to have. It brings the mind into a good emotional state, where enjoying the present comes natural.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful MOOCs</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/moocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/moocs/</guid>
      <description>I found MOOCs very useful throughout my career. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t use them to land new jobs, not in a direct way.
It&amp;rsquo;s more about the power they give me to communicate with people about new and interesting subjects. They are useful because they enable high level conversations between people with interesting ideas.
Why? I believe in education. I believe that education matters a lot in life, and that it can change the world, whereas money can&amp;rsquo;t (though it can be used to foster education).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/05/mentor/</guid>
      <description>Note: I am not a mentor!
What are the three worst difficulties I have in my career right now? How could it be easier? Who has already solved them?
I have never had a mentor, officially. When I look back at my journey as a freelancer I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think that went really well. I went from registering a new account on UpWork to CTO in the Bay Area in 3 years and half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Education Matters to Freelancers</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/blog/2020/03/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/blog/2020/03/education/</guid>
      <description>I thought that highly educated professionals had a hard time finding freelance work. I was wrong. Years later, I have a story to prove it.
What is it that makes an overqualified freelancer appetible to business? What makes entrepreneurs willing to pay the higher rates of freelancers who are PhD, Dr. and more?
If I were to start all over again, what things would I do again because they were proven right, and what mistakes would I want to avoid?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
