<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pietro Grandinetti Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://pete.world/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pietro Grandinetti Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pete.world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Freelancer Journey</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/post/journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/post/journey/</guid>
      <description>I was 23 when I heard the word freelancer the first time. I became fascinated with it, and in the following three years I devoted a great deal of energy and passion towards becoming a freelancer.
I believe I was able to hit some pretty good milestones, but I also hit some very hard walls along the way. I want now to describe in detail the actions I took from the day I decided to become a freelancer, till the day I stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindshift</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/post/mindshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/post/mindshift/</guid>
      <description>Changes in life, sometimes, they just happen.
Why do they more often happen to some people? What traits have these people in common?
For the changes I am talking about, there is one big trait in common: these people are smart.
What is wrong with smart people, why aren&amp;rsquo;t they ever satisfied? Why do they need changes?
To be sure, being content is a great personal quality to have. It brings the mind into a good emotional state, where enjoying the present comes natural.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful MOOCs</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/post/moocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/post/moocs/</guid>
      <description>I found MOOCs very useful throughout my career. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t use them to land new jobs, not in a direct way.
It&amp;rsquo;s more about the power they give me to communicate with people about new and interesting subjects. They are useful because they enable high level conversations between people with interesting ideas.
Why? I believe in education. I believe that education matters a lot in life, and that it can change the world, whereas money can&amp;rsquo;t (though it can be used to foster education).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/post/mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/post/mentor/</guid>
      <description>Note: I am not a mentor!
What are the three worst difficulties I have in my career right now? How could it be easier? Who has already solved them?
I have never had a mentor, officially. When I look back at my journey as a freelancer I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think that went really well. I went from registering a new account on UpWork to CTO in the Bay Area in 3 years and half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Education Matters to Freelancers</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/post/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/post/education/</guid>
      <description>I thought that highly educated professionals had a hard time finding freelance work. I was wrong. Years later, I have a story to prove it.
What is it that makes an overqualified freelancer appetible to business? What makes entrepreneurs willing to pay the higher rates of freelancers who are PhD, Dr. and more?
If I were to start all over again, what things would I do again because they were proven right, and what mistakes would I want to avoid?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://pete.world/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pete.world/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, Pete here. Lifelong learning and outdoor sport is what I do.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big fan of blogs until I realized that I needed one. I write here, though, primarily for me. To be sure, I am happy if I can help somebody else too, but the writing is for me. I need to see what&amp;rsquo;s that I actually know, and to put concepts in writing is the best way to really understand what things I did, what I didn&amp;rsquo;t, and what I missed because I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know about them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>